

# **Argyrios Tsagkalidis**

Date of birth: 06/05/1984

Nationality: Greek

**Gender:** Male

#### CONTACT





(+30) 6979195398

https://github.com/a-tsagkalidis



### **ABOUT ME**

# Brief Description

Experienced IT professional with a background in systems administration, on-site support, and hardware maintenance. I hold a BSc in Electronics Engineering, complemented by certifications in C, Python, cybersecurity, SQL, Azure Cloud, and Cisco networking. Proficient in a range of technologies, including Windows and Linux systems, networking, scripting, software development, CI/CD with Docker containers, and cloud services. A problem-solver with a strong focus on optimizing IT environments, ensuring security, and delivering top-tier remote and on-prem support.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **2024 - CURRENT**

# IT Onsite support engineer Capgemini Engineering | Group IT

Networking | resolving tickets | hardware maintenance | system-room maintenance | user account management | remote and on-site support

Department Global On Site Support (GOSS) | Website https://www.capgemini.com

#### 2022 - 2024

# IT Systems administrator HDL Design House

Networking | resolving tickets | hardware maintenance | user account management | security monitoring | on-site support | system-room maintenance

**Department** Network Operation Center (NOC) | **Website** https://www.linkedin.com/company/hdl-design-house

#### 2018 - 2022

# IT Helpdesk Target Power Group

Equipment implementation | networking | hardware maintenance | user account management | backup planning

#### 2013 - 2018

# Computer hardware repair technician Target Power Electronics

Laptop repairing and maintenance | computer diagnosing | computer assembling/ disassembling | SMD soldering | BGA reworks | IC reprogramming | technical support

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# Computer Science Certificates

- Python Data Structures University of Michigan
- Azure Cloud Services for AZ-900 Microsoft
- CS50X Computer Science Harvard edX
- CS50CS Cybersecurity Harvard edX
- CS50P Programming with Python Harvard edX
- Networking Essentials for CCNA CISCO Network Academy

# English Language Certificates

- LRN C2 Esolnet
- $\bullet$  FCE B2 University of Cambridge
- **BSc in Electronics Engineering** Technological Educational Institute of Thessaloniki Department of Electronics Engineering
  - Specialization on microprocessors/microcomputers field of study.
  - Internship at Papastolou Healthcare Technologies.

Thesis Appliance power usage monitor

School Graduate 1st Vocational School of Xanthi - Analogue Electronics (Field of Study)

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### PROGRAMMING AND SCRIPTING LANGUAGES

Python 3 | C | Assembly | HTML / CSS / JavaScript | SQL | Bash | PowerShell

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

Windows OS since Windows '98 | Linux/Unix-based OS | Working in CLI

### **NOTABLE DEV TOOLS, FRAMEWORKS, AND LIBRARIES**

Flask | Gunicorn | Jinja2 | SQLAlchemy | Locust | Selinium | PyPi Packaging | Bootstrap | JQuery | AJAX | Redis **DEV CLIS AND OTHER TOOLS** 

Git | GitHub Actions | Docker CLI | GitHub CLI | Azure CLI | MS-SQLServer | JSON/YAML | CI/CD | CloudFlare | VS Code

#### **NETWORKS**

VPN | NGINX | Firewalls | SFTP | NAS | SSH | CISCO iOS | RouterOS | DNS | Port Forwarding SYSADMIN TOOLS

MS Azure | MS 365 | MS Intune | DC/AD/GPOs | Self-Hosted Servers | ESET Protect | ServiceNow | MantisBT | PuTT Y | Power Automate | Icinga2 | NoMachine NX Client | LogMeIN

#### **WEB AND CMS**

CMS WordPress | CMS Magento | Web Browsers

### **DRIVING LICENCE**



**Driving Licence:** B

## **MILITARY SERVICES**



Combat Support Arms - Signal Arms